Register of the Ivan D. London papers
Hoover Institution Archives
Ivan D. London papers
1934-2005
83060
Hoover Institution Archives
95 manuscript boxes, 2 card file boxes, 1 oversize box (42.2 linear feet)
Correspondence, writings, questionnaires, interview transcripts, notes, reports, memoranda, and printed matter relating to social conditions in the Soviet Union and China, the Chinese Cultural Revolution, the psychology of the Soviet people and émigrés from the Soviet Union, anti-communist Western propaganda, and the study of science, especially psychology, in the Soviet Union. Includes the papers of Miriam London, wife and collaborator of Ivan D. London.
London, Ivan D., 1913-1983.
London, Miriam.
Access
Boxes 91-98 closed. Eligible to be opened August 5, 2023. The remainder of the collection is open for research.
The Hoover Institution Archives only allows access to copies of audiovisual items. To listen to sound recordings or to view videos or films during your visit, please contact the Archives at least two working days before your arrival. We will then advise you of the accessibility of the material you wish to see or hear. Please note that not all audiovisual material is immediately accessible.
Acquisition Information
Acquired by the Hoover Institution Archives in 1983.
Accruals
Materials may have been added to the collection since this finding aid was prepared. To determine if this has occurred, find the collection in Stanford University's online catalog at http://searchworks.stanford.edu/. Materials have been added to the collection if the number of boxes listed in the online catalog is larger than the number of boxes listed in this finding aid.
Related Collection(s)
Harvard University Russian Research Center interview transcripts, Hoover Institution Archives
Alex Inkeles papers, Hoover Institution Archives
The Harvard Project on the Soviet Social System Online, Harvard College Library
Biographical Note
Dr. Ivan London was an American psychologist. He began his career as a mathematician and then switched to psychology, attracted by the fresh methodological approach of applying mathematics to science.
London joined the Harvard Russian Research Center in 1950 to participate in the Harvard Project on the Soviet Social System (Harvard Emigre Interview Project). Subsequently he joined the faculty at Brooklyn College. There, he and his wife, Miriam, developed their own academic research group that became the Institute of Political Psychology of Brooklyn College, where they carried out further research on Russian refugees, interviewing hundreds of refugees. London also taught social psychology and wrote extensively on the validity of refugee interviewing methods. During the 1960s he continued to interview refugees and published many articles on the subject. He was a leading expert on Soviet psychology with wide contacts with many Soviet psychologists.
In 1963, London decided to apply his interviewing method to Chinese refugees. He spent considerable time in Taiwan and Hong Kong, interviewing refugees and publishing the results. His work with Chinese refugees continued until his death in 1983.
Scope and Content of Collection
The papers document the career of Ivan London, professor of psychology at Brooklyn College. The papers include correspondence, writings, questionnaires, interview transcripts, notes, reports, memoranda, and printed matter relating to social conditions in the Soviet Union and China; the Chinese Cultural Revolution; the mindset of the Soviet people and émigrés from the Soviet Union; anti-communist Western propaganda; and the study of science, especially psychology, in the Soviet Union.
The Inwood Project on Intercultural Communication (European Group of Harvard University) Records series makes up the main body of the collection. The series is divided into three parts by interview type: A-Schedule (Problem of Communication between Peoples), B-Schedule (Special Topics Interviews), and D-Schedule (Soviet Psychological Research). The series consists of interview transcripts, completed questionnaires, reports, and working interview notes, and also includes Chinese refugees project documents consisting of responses to questionnaires and correspondence.
The Correspondence series mainly contains London's letters to and from refugees and researchers associated with the Harvard Project on the Soviet Social System. The Writings series contains materials written, translated, and edited by London. These represent a variety of topics in sociology and psychology, including religion, education, and science in the Soviet Union, as well as a contemporary analysis of history and psychology.
The collection also includes the papers of Miriam London, wife and collaborator of Ivan D. London, including her correspondence and writings.
Propaganda, Anti-communist.; Psychology--Soviet Union.; Psychology--China.; Public opinion--Soviet Union.; Public opinion--China.; Soviet Union--Emigration and immigration.; China--Emigration and immigration.; Science--Soviet Union.; China--History--Cultural Revolution, 1966-1976.; China--Social conditions.; Soviet Union--Social conditions.
- Biographical File, 1940-1983 (Box-folder 1: 1)
  Scope and Contents note
  Includes biography, college certificates, and curriculum vitae.
- Correspondence, 1944-1985
  Arrangement Statement
  Arranged alphabetically by correspondent.
  - General, 1951-1981 (Box-folder 1: 2-7)
  - American Friends of Russian Freedom, Inc., 1955 (Box-folder 1: 8)
  - Anokhin, P. K., 1966-1967 (Box-folder 1: 9)
  - Arnold, Theodor, 1953-1955 (Box-folder 1: 10)
  - Astrakhantsev, 1963 (Box-folder 1: 11)
  - Bagration-Mukhranskii, Teimuraz, 1954-1957 (Box-folder 1: 12)
  - Bakhtalovskii, Boris, 1951 (Box-folder 1: 13)
  - Bakich, N., 1966 (Box-folder 1: 14)
  - Barghoorn, Frederick C., 1967 (Box-folder 1: 15)
  - Bassin, Filipp V., 1959-1969 (Box-folder 1: 16)
  - Batalin, V., 1962 (Box-folder 1: 17)
  - Batiuk, Maria, 1958 (Box-folder 1: 18)
  - Bauer, Raymond A., 1948-1956 (Box-folder 1: 19)
  - Bauman, Michael, 1954 (Box-folder 1: 20)
  - Baumshtein, A., 1969 (Box-folder 1: 21)
  - Beritashvili, Ivan S., 1967-1969 (Box-folder 1: 22-23)
    Includes publications.
  - Bervik, A., 1966 (Box-folder 1: 24)
  - Bikard, Vladimir, 1967-1968 (Box-folder 1: 25)
  - Biriukov, Dmitrii, 1968 (Box-folder 1: 26)
  - Bondarenko, I., 1964 (Box-folder 1: 27)
  - Boring, Edwin G., 1951-1959 (Box-folder 1: 28-29)
  - Cantril, Hadley, 1947-1957 (Box-folder 1: 30-31)
  - Chan, Nim-chun, 1975-1976 (Box-folder 2: 1-2)
  - Chan, Sze-lam, 1975-1976 (Box-folder 2: 3)
  - Chen, Yung-sheng, 1969-1971 (Box-folder 2: 4)
    Includes Facts about the Situation on the Chinese Mainland in 91 Questions and Answers by Chen Yung-sheng, and clippings.
  - Chepinoka, L., 1956-1959 (Box-folder 2: 5)
  - Cherkin, Arthur, 1966 (Box-folder 2: 6)
  - Cherniavskii, Alex, 1966 (Box-folder 2: 7)
  - Chonomskii (Chounomski), M., 1956 (Box-folder 2: 8)
  - Chugunov, T. K., 1959-1967 (Box-folder 2: 9)
  - David, Henry P., 1962-1963 (Box-folder 2: 10)
  - Deptula, Nancy, 1956-1957 (Box-folder 2: 11)
  - DeWitt, Nicholas, 1957 (Box-folder 2: 12)
  - Diefenbach, William, 1962 (Box-folder 2: 13)
  - Dilov, A., 1953 (Box-folder 2: 14)
  - Dol'berg, A., 1957-1959 (Box-folder 2: 15)
  - Dubynec, I., 1953 (Box-folder 2: 16)
  - Ebon, Martin (Parapsychology Foundation), 1963-1964 (Box-folder 2: 17)
  - Emmich, Eugene, 1953 (Box-folder 2: 18)
  - Fizer, Mary and John, 1956 (Box-folder 2: 19)
  - Fridman, Ivan, 1954-1955 (Box-folder 2: 20)
  - Gardner, Martin, 1966 (Box-folder 2: 21)
  - Gregory, Viktor (Victor), 1957-1959 (Box-folder 2: 22)
  - Griazev, I. V., 1966 (Box-folder 2: 23)
  - Grigor'ev, Ivan M., 1954-1958 (Box-folder 2: 24-26)
  - Haken, H., 1980-1981 (Box-folder 2: 27)
  - Hall, E. K., 1954-1957 (Box-folder 3: 1)
  - Hanfmann, Genia, 1957-1958 (Box-folder 3: 2)
  - Heyer, 1957 (Box-folder 3: 3)
  - Holub, V., 1953-1958 (Box-folder 3: 4)
  - Hsu, Robert, 1973 (Box-folder 3: 5)
  - Hughes, Richard, 1972-1984 (Box-folder 3: 6-7)
    Includes clippings.
  - Hunter, T., 1951 (Box-folder 3: 8)
  - Iakovlev, B., 1955-1956 (Box-folder 3: 9)
  - Iasnyi (Jasnyi), V., 1955-1957 (Box-folder 3: 10)
  - Inkeles, Alex, 1956 (Box-folder 3: 11)
  - Jagoda, Harry, 1973 (Box-folder 3: 12)
  - Johnson, E. Parker, 1949 (Box-folder 3: 13)
  - Johnson, Harry M., 1944-1950 (Box-folder 3: 14)
  - Kamkin, Viktor, 1956-1958 (Box-folder 3: 15)
  - Kapusta, F., 1963 (Box-folder 3: 16)
  - Kerensky, Oleg Aleksandrovich, 1957-1958 (Box-folder 3: 17)
  - Khangadzhev (Hangajew), 1954-1955 (Box-folder 3: 18)
  - Khokhlov, E. N., 1955-1961 (Box-folder 3: 19)
  - Klimov, G., 1953 (Box-folder 3: 23)
  - Kliuev, N., 1953-1956 (Box-folder 3: 20-22)
  - Konstantinov, D., 1957-1960 (Box-folder 3: 24)
  - Koriakov (Koriakoff), M., 1953 (Box-folder 3: 25)
  - Korol'kevich, S., 1951 (Box-folder 3: 26)
  - Koval'chuk (Kowalciuk), A., 1955 (Box-folder 3: 27)
  - Koval'skii, M., 1959-1960 (Box-folder 3: 28)
  - Kramarovskii, A., 1955-1960 (Box-folder 3: 29)
  - Krivskii, A., 1965 (Box-folder 3: 30)
  - Krupenko, Aleksandr, 1951 (Box-folder 3: 31)
  - Kuo, Kenneth (K'un-Jen), 1969-1973 (Box-folder 4: 1-6)
  - Kuo, Kun-chung, 1968-1970 (Box-folder 4: 7)
  - Kurdziuk, I., 1953-1955 (Box-folder 4: 8)
  - Kurganov, 1954 (Box-folder 4: 9)
  - La Dany, L., 1970-1985 (Box-folder 4: 10-14)
  - Lam, Hong-leung, 1976 (Box-folder 5: 1)
    Includes his poems and essays.
  - Langfeld, Herbert, 1944-1952 (Box-folder 5: 2)
  - Langmuir, Irving, 1946-1947 (Box-folder 5: 3)
  - Lanier, Lyle H., 1951 (Box-folder 5: 4)
  - Lavrushin, P. F., 1970 (Box-folder 5: 5)
  - Lee, Hon-Sham, 1977 (Box-folder 5: 6)
  - Leeper, Robert, 1948 (Box-folder 5: 7)
  - Lenchevskii (Lenchevsky), 1962 (Box-folder 5: 8)
  - Lesik (Lesyak), Trofim, 1953 (Box-folder 5: 9)
  - Li, Chen-sheng, 1973-1976 (Box-folder 5: 10)
  - Li, Ziren, 1981 (Box-folder 5: 11)
  - Liang, Tung, 1977-1981 (Box-folder 5: 12)
  - Lin, Paul (Pao-hua), 1978-1980 (Box-folder 5: 13)
  - London, David, 1958-1959 (Box-folder 5: 14)
  - Los', N., 1956 (Box-folder 5: 15)
  - Luther, Michael, 1951 (Box-folder 5: 16)
  - Lybrand, W., 1955 (Box-folder 5: 17)
  - Lyzlov (Lyslov), Evgenii, 1953-1954 (Box-folder 5: 18)
  - Machover, Solomon, 1948-1949 (Box-folder 5: 19)
  - Mais, Walter, 1959-1961 (Box-folder 5: 20)
  - Makarov, P. O., 1960-1969 (Box-folder 5: 21-22)
  - Makous, Walter, 1967-1968 (Box-folder 5: 23)
  - Markov (Markoff), M., 1952-1957 (Box-folder 5: 24)
  - Markus, Michael, 1952 (Box-folder 5: 25)
  - Marsh, Robert, 1960 (Box-folder 5: 26)
  - Maruyama, Kinya, 1950 (Box-folder 5: 27)
  - Maslenikov, L., 1958 (Box-folder 5: 28)
  - Maslov (Maslow), Will, 1960 (Box-folder 5: 29)
  - Matisov, Vasilii, 1960 (Box-folder 5: 30)
  - Mayer, Gerald, 1953 (Box-folder 5: 31)
  - McKinney, Russel, 1954-1958 (Box-folder 5: 32-33, 6: 1-2)
  - Meierkhov (Meyerhoff), Howard A., 1951-1952 (Box-folder 6: 4)
  - Meiers, Joseph I., 1951-1952 (Box-folder 6: 3)
  - Mezenchuk, E., 1965 (Box-folder 6: 5)
  - Mikhailov (Michajloff), George, 1956 (Box-folder 6: 6)
  - Mikhailov-Metz, S., 1951 (Box-folder 6: 7)
  - Milk (Mylk), Eugen, 1954 (Box-folder 6: 8)
  - Miller, James, 1949-1960 (Box-folder 6: 9)
  - Mills, Clarence, 1949 (Box-folder 6: 10)
  - Mironov, N., 1957 (Box-folder 6: 11)
  - Miroshnichenko, S., 1952 (Box-folder 6: 12)
  - Miroshnikov, Ivan, 1953-1954 (Box-folder 6: 13)
  - Mitchell, Russell, 1950-1952 (Box-folder 6: 14)
  - Mlakovii, Mikhail, 1953 (Box-folder 6: 15)
  - Moch, R., 1952 (Box-folder 6: 16)
  - Morgan, Clifford, 1961 (Box-folder 6: 17)
  - Moscovici, Serge, 1952-1953 (Box-folder 6: 18)
  - Mowrer, C. Hobart, 1948 (Box-folder 6: 19)
  - Murchison, Carl, 1949-1952 (Box-folder 6: 20)
  - Nashpiz, C., 1958 (Box-folder 6: 21)
  - Natadze, R. G., 1964 (Box-folder 6: 22)
  - Naumov, Eduard K., 1966-1969 (Box-folder 6: 23)
  - Naumov, Sergei, 1966 (Box-folder 6: 24)
  - Newcomb, Theodore M., 1953-1955 (Box-folder 6: 25)
  - Nie, Shimao, 1980 (Box-folder 6: 26)
  - Nixon, Lewis M., 1954 (Box-folder 6: 27)
  - Noble, Clyde, 1949-1950 (Box-folder 6: 28)
  - Novak-Deker, N., 1953-1958 (Box-folder 6: 29-31)
  - Novomeiskii, A. S., 1965-1974 (Box-folder 6: 32)
  - Oak, Cerard N., 1959 (Box-folder 6: 33)
  - Ol'shanskii, Boris, 1953-1957 (Box-folder 6: 34)
  - Orlich, V., 1951-1966 (Box-folder 6: 35)
  - Orr, Helen, 1959-1960 (Box-folder 6: 36)
  - Osipov, T., 1957-1958 (Box-folder 6: 37)
  - Pavlov, 1965 (Box-folder 6: 38)
  - Pelayo, A., 1961-1966 (Box-folder 6: 39)
  - Peleshenko, Zakhar, 1951 (Box-folder 6: 40)
  - Perezhivalin, P., 1961 (Box-folder 6: 41)
  - Petrov, Nikolai, 1958-1966 (Box-folder 7: 1)
  - Petrov-Skitalets, E., 1959-1964 (Box-folder 7: 2)
  - Petrushev, Peter, 1964 (Box-folder 7: 3)
  - Pieron, H., 1952 (Box-folder 7: 4)
  - Pirozhkova, V., 1957-1958 (Box-folder 7: 5)
  - Poire (Puare), Inna V., 1951 (Box-folder 7: 6)
    Includes copies of documents regarding the Soviet government's discrimination against her, 1925-1940.
  - Poltoratskii, Nikolai, 1955-1960 (Box-folder 7: 7)
  - Popel', Roman, 1956 (Box-folder 7: 8)
  - Pratt, Carroll, 1947-1950 (Box-folder 7: 9)
  - Rabinovich (Rabinowitch), Eugene, 1951-1952 (Box-folder 7: 10)
  - Rappoport, D., 1952 (Box-folder 7: 11)
  - Rausen, B., 1954-1955 (Box-folder 7: 12)
  - Redlich, R., 1955 (Box-folder 7: 13)
  - Remin, P., 1957 (Box-folder 7: 14)
  - Reshetar, John, 1958 (Box-folder 7: 15)
  - Revay, Julian, 1953 (Box-folder 7: 16)
  - Reymert, Martin, 1948-1950 (Box-folder 7: 17)
  - Rodger, A., 1952 (Box-folder 7: 18)
  - Romanov (Romanoff), Stephen, 1954 (Box-folder 7: 19)
  - Ryckmans, Pierre, 1976-1982 (Box-folder 7: 20-21)
  - Rudin, Stanley A., 1958 (Box-folder 7: 22)
  - Rudnitskii, Ivan, 1951 (Box-folder 7: 23)
  - Rudovskii, Arkadii, 1953-1954 (Box-folder 7: 24)
  - Saburova, Irina, 1953 (Box-folder 7: 25)
  - Sanford, Fillmore, 1954 (Box-folder 7: 26)
  - Sargeant, Howland H., 1954-1959 (Box-folder 7: 27)
    Includes The Inwood Institute's Hanover Round Table, summary report, 1954.
  - Sarkisian, G., 1966 (Box-folder 7: 28)
  - Savel'ev, Aleksandr, 1954 (Box-folder 7: 29)
    Includes Satirikon, No. 25, 1953.
  - Savitskii, Viktor, 1953 (Box-folder 7: 30)
  - Schmidt, Albert C., 1953-1982 (Box-folder 7: 31-32)
  - Schwartz, H., 1953 (Box-folder 7: 33)
  - Serdakovskii, Lev, 1961 (Box-folder 7: 34)
  - Serebriakov, P. I., 1956 (Box-folder 7: 35)
  - Sharpe, Myron, 1959-1960 (Box-folder 8: 1)
  - Shubin, F., 1964 (Box-folder 8: 2)
  - Shurka, M., 1951 (Box-folder 8: 3)
  - Simirenko, Alex, 1966-1968 (Box-folder 8: 4)
  - Sinii, Ivan, 1957 (Box-folder 8: 5)
  - Skellenger, Elizabeth, 1957 (Box-folder 8: 6)
  - Skripitsa, Ivan, 1959-1960 (Box-folder 8: 7)
  - Slusser, Robert M., 1954 (Box-folder 8: 8)
  - Smirnov, M. S., 1966 (Box-folder 8: 9)
  - Smirnov, V., 1953-1954 (Box-folder 8: 10)
  - Smith, Brewster M., 1957-1959 (Box-folder 8: 11)
  - Smith, Martha, 1959 (Box-folder 8: 12)
  - Snyder, H., 1951-1956 (Box-folder 8: 13)
  - Sokolov-Samarin, V., 1954-1960 (Box-folder 8: 14)
  - Solomon, Richard, 1958 (Box-folder 8: 15)
  - Solov'eva, Valentina, 1951 (Box-folder 8: 16)
  - Spagnoli, 1960 (Box-folder 8: 17)
  - Sprow, Allen, 1957 (Box-folder 8: 18)
  - Stepanova, N., 1966 (Box-folder 8: 19)
  - Stevens, Leslie, 1953-1954 (Box-folder 8: 20)
  - Stoller, E., 1959 (Box-folder 8: 21)
  - Taylor, Blair, 1953 (Box-folder 8: 22)
  - Teodorovich, Nadezhda, 1957-1966 (Box-folder 8: 23)
  - Thorngate, Warren, 1978-1983 (Box-folder 8: 24)
  - Tietz, John W., 1949-1958 (Box-folder 8: 25)
  - Timashev (Timasheff), N. S., 1956 (Box-folder 8: 26)
  - Tolstoy, Aleksandra, 1953-1954 (Box-folder 8: 27)
  - Tolstoy, Lydia (Lidiia), 1953-1954 (Box-folder 8: 28)
  - Tomashevskii, Mikhael, 1951 (Box-folder 8: 29)
  - Tompkins, Warwick M., 1952 (Box-folder 8: 30)
  - Tsumita, Toru and Hiroko, 1957-1958 (Box-folder 8: 31)
  - Ul'ianov (Ulynov), 1954 (Box-folder 8: 32)
  - United States Information Agency, 1957-1958 (Box-folder 8: 33)
  - Utechin, S. V., 1958 (Box-folder 8: 34)
  - Valentine, Willard, 1944-1947 (Box-folder 8: 35)
  - Vasil'ev, Lev, 1954-1955 (Box-folder 8: 36)
  - Vasil'ev (Vassiliew), Mikhail, 1951 (Box-folder 8: 37)
  - Vazagov, V., 1957-1963 (Box-folder 8: 38)
  - Vezlenkov, S., 1953 (Box-folder 8: 39)
  - Vicas, G., 1953 (Box-folder 8: 40)
  - Viktorov, V., 1963 (Box-folder 8: 41)
  - Vitello, Andrea, 1959-1960 (Box-folder 8: 42)
  - Vladimir, Ieromonakh, 1954 (Box-folder 8: 43)
  - Voloshin, S., 1969 (Box-folder 8: 44)
  - Wang, Kuang-ta, 1970 (Box-folder 9: 1)
  - Weinbaum, Mark Efimovich, 1965-1973 (Box-folder 9: 2)
  - Wheeler, Raymond, 1950 (Box-folder 9: 3)
  - White, Ralph, 1957 (Box-folder 9: 4)
  - Zabolotskii, Nikolai, 1949-1964 (Box-folder 9: 5-20)
    Includes Zabolotskii family letters and photographs.
  - Zakharias, P., 1956 (Box-folder 9: 21)
  - Zamir, Peretts, 1958-1960 (Box-folder 9: 22)
  - Zaporozhets, A. V., 1954 (Box-folder 9: 23)
  - Zerchukov (Zerchykov), M., 1958-1959 (Box-folder 9: 24)
  - Zhuchkov, M., 1955 (Box-folder 9: 25)
  - Ziren, Li, 1981 (Box-folder 9: 26)
- Inwood Project on Intercultural Communication (European Group of Harvard University Project on the Soviet Social System) Records, 1938-1986
  - A-Schedule interviews (Problem of Communication between Peoples) materials, 1950-1966
    Includes structured interviews conducted according to an interview guide (A-Schedule) and covering the individual's life history, experience in certain selected areas of Soviet life, and attitude toward a wide range of topics. Arranged alphabetically under original headings.
    - Analyses and evaluation of responses, 1955-1956 (Box-folder 10: 1-7)
    - Analysis of interviews conducted in Chile, 1954 (Box-folder 10: 8)
    - Attitude toward survey themes material, 1954-1956
      - Flash survey responses, 1954-1955
        Arranged sequentially by brochure number of questionnaires completed by interviewers.
        - 1-450, 1954-1955 (Box-folder 10: 11-14, 11: 1-6)
        - 702-1483, 1955 (Box-folder 11: 7-12, 12: 1-14, 13: 1-13)
      - Summary and research memoranda, 1955-1956 (Box-folder 14: 1-16)
    - Basic written questionnaire, 1953 (Box-folder 14: 17)
    - Chart of survey conducted in Argentina, 1955-1956 (Box-folder 15: 1)
    - Coding system and memoranda, 1951-1952 (Box-folder 15: 2-4)
    - Communist semantics research note, circa 1955 (Box-folder 15: 5)
    - Completed questionnaires, 1954
      - 1-150 (Box-folder 15: 6-10, 16: 1-9, 17: 1-8, 18: 1-7)
      - 402-450 (Box-folder 18: 8, 19: 1-9)
      - 700-1476 (Boxes 20-32)
      - 2000 (Box-folder 33: 1)
    - Confidential evaluations of project, 1957 (Box-folder 33: 2)
    - Data book, 1957 (Box-folder 33: 3)
    - Forms and instructions, 1953-1963 (Box-folder 33: 4-7)
    - Interview transcripts conducted in Germany, 1953-1957 (Box-folder 33: 8)
    - List of participants in survey, 1956-1963 (Box-folder 33: 9)
    - List of respondents by brochure number, circa 1950 (Box-folder 33: 10)
    - Master code list, 1951 (Box-folder 33: 11)
    - Medical questionnaire, circa 1950 (Box-folder 33: 12)
    - Nationality questionnaires, forms, and instructions, circa 1950 (Box-folder 33: 13)
    - Notes on codings, 1950 (Box-folder 34: 1)
    - Oral history questionnaire, 1950 (Box-folder 34: 2-3)
    - Personnel, 1951 (Box-folder 34: 4)
    - Philadelphia interview protocols, 1953 (Box-folder 34: 5)
    - Project evaluation forms, circa 1950 (Box-folder 34: 6)
    - Project evaluation responses, A-Z, 1951-1963 (Boxes 34-38)
      Includes correspondence, clippings, and writings.
    - Questionnaire for repatriated Spaniards, circa 1960 (Box-folder 39: 1)
    - Questionnaire evaluation with factor analysis, 1954-1961 (Box-folder 39: 2-10)
    - "Reaction Spectrum for the Inwood Project Themes,", 1956 (Box-folder 39: 11-12)
    - Replies to Ivan London's appeal through Novoe Russkoe Slovo to Russian immigrants to participate in a sociological survey, 1951-1966 (Box-folder 40: 1-11)
    - Research proposal, studies A-Z, 1956 (Box-folder 40: 12-24, 41: 1-5)
    - Research protocols, 1954-1956 (Box-folder 41: 6-11)
    - Sentence completion test forms, 1956-1957 (Box-folder 41: 12-13)
  - B-Schedule interviews (Special Topics Interviews) materials, 1938-1969
    Includes special topic interviews on economics, family, government, stratification, nationalities, wartime occupation, partisan movements, and professions. Arranged alphabetically by topic.
    - American policy toward Cuba, 1962 (Box-folder 41: 14-16, 42: 1-13)
      Includes answers to questionnaire.
    - American policy toward the Soviet Union, 1955-1963 (Box-folder 42: 14-16, 43: 1-10)
      Includes answers to questionnaire and protocol memoranda.
    - American policy toward Vietnam, 1965 (Box-folder 43: 11-13, 44: 1-15)
    - Attitude toward themes, A-Z, 1964-1969 (Box-folder 45: 1-10)
      Includes research participants’ review on special topics. Arranged alphabetically by name.
    - Attitude toward the West, 1956-1957 (Box-folder 45: 11-13, 46: 1-3)
      Includes answers to questionnaire and notes.
    - Berlin crisis of 1961, 1961-1963 (Box-folder 46: 4-14)
      Includes answers to questionnaire and clippings.
    - British sailors in Leningrad, 1955-1957 (Box-folder 46: 15)
      Includes correspondence, clippings, and printed matter.
    - Contacts of Soviet citizens with foreigners, 1960-1963 (Box-folder 46: 16-18, 47: 1-6)
      Includes correspondence.
    - Human nature, 1954-1957 (Box-folder 47: 7-11, 48: 1-2)
      Includes unofficial memoranda, research material, and correspondence.
    - Hungarian uprising, 1956-1957 (Box-folder 48: 3-6)
      Includes correspondence and printed matter.
    - "Is it 'Peaceful' or 'Coexistence'?," readers' comments on New York Times' article by Philip E. Mosely, 1961 (Box-folder 48: 7-12, 49: 1-5)
    - Nationalism and anti-Semitism in Ukraine, 1954-1958 (Box-folder 49: 6-9)
      Includes correspondence, writings, and printed matter.
    - The New Chinese Skin Game, by C. L. Sulzberger, article discussion among Chinese and Russian émigrés, 1963-1966 (Box-folder 60: 1-13)
    - Oleg: A Member of the Soviet "Golden Youth", by Helen Beier, an article to discuss, 1955-1962 (Box-folder 49: 10-13, 50: 1-9)
      Includes correspondence, writings, clippings, and notes.
    - Recent events in the USSR, 1961-1963 (Box-folder 50: 10-16)
      Includes correspondence of response from Moscow participants.
    - Religion in the Soviet Union, 1955-1965
      - Correspondence, 1956-1958
        - Alekseev, Vasilii, 1956-1957 (Box-folder 51: 1)
        - Anastasii, Mitrpolitan, 1957-1958 (Box-folder 51: 2)
        - Anderson, Paul B., 1957 (Box-folder 51: 3)
        - Andreev, Ivan Mikhailovich, 1957-1958 (Box-folder 51: 4)
        - Curties, John, 1957 (Box-folder 51: 5)
        - Heyer, F., 1956-1957 (Box-folder 51: 6)
        - Hollberg, Wilhelm, 1956-1957 (Box-folder 51: 7)
        - Il'inskii, P., 1957 (Box-folder 51: 8)
        - Kartashov (Kartachoff), Anton, 1957 (Box-folder 51: 9)
        - Kishkovskii (Kishkovsky), Aleksandr Ivanovich, 1956-1957 (Box-folder 51: 10)
        - Konstantinow (Konstantinov), Dmitrii, 1956-1957 (Box-folder 51: 11)
        - Liven (Lieven), Aleksandr Andreeevich, 1956-1957 (Box-folder 51: 12)
        - Lyzlov (lyslov), Evgenii, 1956-1957 (Box-folder 51: 13)
        - Osipov, T., 1957 (Box-folder 51: 14)
        - Rar, Gleb Aleksandrovich, 1956-1957 (Box-folder 51: 15)
        - Shmeman (Schmeman), Aleksandr (Alexander), 1957 (Box-folder 51: 16)
        - Struve, Nikita, 1957-1958 (Box-folder 51: 17)
        - Timashev (Timasheff), Nikolai Sergeevish, 1956-1957 (Box-folder 51: 18)
      - Questionnaire forms, 1955 (Box-folder 51: 19)
      - Religious groups, 1956-1962 (Box-folder 51: 20-23)
      - Research material and reports, 1955-1965 (Box-folder 52: 1-14)